[
    {"question": "Which insect shorted out an early supercomputer and inspired 'bug'?", "options":["Moth","Roach","Fly","Japanese Beetle"], "answer":"Moth"},
    {"question": "Which county cricket side is based at Chester-le-Street?","options": ["Warwickshire","Durham","Northants","Leicestershire"],"answer": "Durham"},
    {"question": "Which monarch was known as 'the wisest fool in Christendom'?","options": ["James I","Charles I","Edward I","Henry I"],"answer": "James I"},
    {"question": "Which king was married to Eleanor of Aquitaine?","options": ["Henry I","Henry II","Richard I","Henry V"],"answer": "Henry II"},
    {"question": "Oberon is a satellite of which planet?","options": ["Mercury","Neptune","Uranus","Mars"],"answer": "Uranus"},
    {"question": "In 1912, former US President Theodore Roosevelt was a candidate for which political party?","options": ["Bull Moose","Bull Dog","Bull Elephant","Bull Frog"],"answer": "Bull Moose"},
    {"question": "Tomas Masaryk was the first President of which country?","options": ["Czechoslovakia","Poland","Hungary","Yugoslavia"],"answer": "Czechoslovakia"},
    {"question": "If you planted the seeds of 'Quercus robur', what would grow?","options": ["Trees","Flowers","Vegetables","Grain"],"answer": "Trees"},
    {"question": "A number one followed by one hundred zeros is known by what name?","options": ["Googol","Megatron","Gigabit","Nanomole"],"answer": "Googol"},
    {"question": "Which scientific unit is named after an Italian nobleman?","options": ["Pascal","Ohm","Volt","Hertz"],"answer": "Volt"},
    {"question": "What was the profession of the composer Borodin?","options": ["Naval captain","Chemist","Lawyer","Chef"],"answer": "Chemist"},
    {"question": "Which of these is a butterfly, not a moth?","options": ["Mother Shipton","Red Underwing","Burnished Brass","Speckled Wood"],"answer": "Speckled Wood"},
    {"question": "Which of these is not one of the American Triple Crown horse races?","options": ["Arlington Million","Belmont Stakes","Kentucky Derby","Preakness Stakes"],"answer": "Arlington Million"},
    {"question": "Translated from the Latin, what is the motto of the United States?","options": ["In God we trust","One out of many","All as one","Striving together"],"answer": "One out of many"},
    {"question": "Who was the first man to travel into space twice?","options": ["Vladimir Titov","Michael Collins","Gus Grissom","Yuri Gagarin"],"answer": "Gus Grissom"},
    {"question": "Which boxer was famous for striking the gong in the introduction to J. Arthur Rank films?","options": ["Bombardier Billy Wells","Freddie Mills","Terry Spinks","Don Cockell"],"answer": "Bombardier Billy Wells"},
    {"question": "Which of these UK prime ministers never served as foreign secretary?","options": ["Winston Churchill","Alec Douglas-Home","Anthony Eden","Harold Macmillan"],"answer": "Winston Churchill"},
    {"question": "Which of these people was born the same year as Queen Elizabeth II?","options": ["Audrey Hepburn","Judy Garland","Julie Andrews","Marilyn Monroe"],"answer": "Marilyn Monroe"},
    {"question": "In the history of motor sport, which of these iconic races was held first?","options": ["Le Mans 24 Hours","Monaco Grand Prix","Indy 500","Isle of Man TT"],"answer": "Isle of Man TT"},
    {"question": "In 1718, which pirate died in battle off the coast of what is now North Carolina?","options": ["Calico Jack","Blackbeard","Bartholomew Roberts","Captain Kidd"],"answer": "Blackbeard"},
    {"question": "Which of these words, each coined by a famous writer, was derived from the title of a fairy tale about three princes?","options": ["Pandemonium","Serendipity","Utopia","Yahoo"],"answer": "Serendipity"},
    {"question": "On February 22, 1989, what group won the first Grammy award for Best Hard Rock/Metal Performance?","options": ["Metallica","AC/DC","Living Colour","Jethro Tull"],"answer": "Jethro Tull"},
    {"question": "Which of these U.S. Presidents appeared on the television series \"Laugh-In\"?","options": ["Lyndon Johnson","Richard Nixon","Jimmy Carter","Gerald Ford"],"answer": "Richard Nixon"},
    {"question": "In what language was Anne Frank's original diary first published?","options": ["Dutch","English","French","German"],"answer": "Dutch"},
    {"question": "The Earth is approximately how many miles away from the Sun?","options": ["9.3 million","39 million","93 million","193 million"],"answer": "93 million"},
    {"question": "In what country are all U.S. Major League baseballs currently manufactured?","options": ["Costa Rica","Haiti","Dominican Republic","Cuba"],"answer": "Costa Rica"},
    {"question": "What Shakespeare character says, \"Something is rotten in the state of Denmark\"?","options": ["Hamlet","Marcellus","Horatio","Laertes"],"answer": "Marcellus"},
    {"question": "Which of the following pieces of currency was the first to use the motto \"In God We Trust\"?","options": ["Nickel","One dollar bill","Two-cent piece","Five dollar bill"],"answer": "Two-cent piece"},
    {"question": "Who was the first NFL player to answer \"I'm going to Disneyland\" in the popular series of TV ads?","options": ["Doug Williams","Marcus Allen","Phil Simms","Joe Montana"],"answer": "Phil Simms"},
    {"question": "What is the last word in the Old Testament?","options": ["Forever","True","Prayer","Curse"],"answer": "Curse"},
    {"question": "Before the American colonies switched to the Gregorian calendar, on what date did their new year start?","options": ["March 25","July 1","September 25","December 1"],"answer": "March 25"},
    {"question": "Which of the following men does not have a chemical element named for him?","options": ["Albert Einstein","Niels Bohr","Isaac Newton","Enrico Fermi"],"answer": "Isaac Newton"},
    {"question": "Which of the following landlocked countries is entirely contained within another country?","options": ["Lesotho","Burkina Faso","Mongolia","Luxembourg"],"answer": "Lesotho"},
    {"question": "In the children's book series, where is Paddington Bear originally from?","options": ["India","Peru","Canada","Iceland"],"answer": "Peru"},
    {"question": "What best-selling author was born Howard Allen O'Brien?","options": ["Danielle Steel","Anne Rice","J.K. Rowling","Toni Morrison"],"answer": "Anne Rice"},
    {"question": "In the U.S., the Sony Walkman personal cassette player was originally marketed in 1979 under what name?","options": ["Soundabout","Listener","Eardrummer","Stowaway"],"answer": "Soundabout"},
    {"question": "According to the United Nations, in what year was the world's population half of its present total?","options": ["1950","1960","1970","1940"],"answer": "1960"},
    {"question": "During the Cold War, the U.S. government built a bunker to house Congress under what golf resort?","options": ["The Breakers","The Greenbrier","Pinehurst","The Broadmoor"],"answer": "The Greenbrier"},
    {"question": "What plant is named after the first U.S. ambassador to Mexico, who brought it to the U.S.?","options": ["Fuchsia","Juniper","Camellia","Poinsettia"],"answer": "Poinsettia"},
    {"question": "Which of these network news anchors began his career at age 9, hosting a children's radio show?","options": ["Peter Jennings","Tom Brokaw","Dan Rather","Ted Koppel"],"answer": "Peter Jennings"},  
    {"question": "Who is the only winner of the Nobel Peace Prize to decline the prize?","options": ["Albert Schweitzer","Le Duc Tho","Andrei Sakharov","Aung San Suu Kyi"],"answer": "Le Duc Tho"},
    {"question": "People who have a marked physical reaction to beautiful art are said to suffer from what syndrome?","options": ["Proust Syndrome","Jerusalem Syndrome","Stendhal's Syndrome","Beckett's Syndrome"],"answer": "Stendhal's Syndrome"},
    {"question": "Who is credited with inventing the first mass-produced helicopter?","options": ["Igor Sikorsky","Elmer Sperry","Ferdinand von Zeppelin","Gottlieb Daimler"],"answer": "Igor Sikorsky"},
    {"question": "What letter must appear at the beginning of the registration number of all non-military aircraft in the U.S.?","options": ["N","A","U","L"],"answer": "N"},
    {"question": "In the TV series \"The Brady Bunch\", what is Carol Brady's maiden name?","options": ["Martin","Tyler","Nelson","Franklin"],"answer": "Tyler"},
    {"question": "How many days make up a non-leap year in the Islamic calendar?","options": ["365","400","354","376"],"answer": "354"},
    {"question": "What club did astronaut Alan Shepard use to make his famous golf shot on the moon?","options": ["Nine iron","Sand wedge","Six iron","Seven iron"],"answer": "Six iron"},
    {"question": "Who is the only Nobel laureate to win an Academy Award?","options": ["John Steinbeck","Jean-Paul Sartre","George Bernard Shaw","Toni Morrison"],"answer": "George Bernard Shaw"},
    {"question": "Famous pediatrician and author Dr. Benjamin Spock won an Olympic gold medal in what sport?","options": ["Swimming","Rowing","Fencing","Sailing"],"answer": "Rowing"},
    {"question": "During WWII, U.S. soldiers used the first commercial aerosol cans to hold what?","options": ["Cleaning fluid","Antiseptic","Insecticide","Shaving cream"],"answer": "Insecticide"},
    {"question": "The U.S. icon \"Uncle Sam\" was based on Samuel Wilson, who worked during the War of 1812 as a what?","options": ["Meat inspector","Mail deliverer","Historian","Weapons mechanic"],"answer": "Meat inspector"},
    {"question": "Who did artist Grant Wood use as the model for the farmer in his classic painting \"American Gothic\"?","options": ["Traveling salesman","Local sheriff","His dentist","His butcher"],"answer": "His dentist"},
    {"question": "The song \"God Bless America\" was originally written for what 1918 musical?","options": ["Oh, Lady! Lady!","Yip, Yip, Yaphank","Blossom Time","Watch Your Step"],"answer": "Yip, Yip, Yaphank"},
    {"question": "Now used to refer to a cat, the word \"tabby\" is derived from the name of a district of what world capital?","options": ["Baghdad","New Delhi","Cairo","Moscow"],"answer": "Baghdad"},
    {"question": "Which of these ships was not one of the three taken over by colonists during the Boston Tea Party?","options": ["Eleanor","Dartmouth","Beaver","William"],"answer": "William"},
    {"question": "Khrushchev's famous 1960 \"shoe-banging\" outburst at the U.N. was in response to a delegate from what nation?","options": ["Australia","The Netherlands","The Philippines","Turkey"],"answer": "The Philippines"},
    {"question": "For ordering his favorite beverages on demand, LBJ had four buttons installed in the Oval Office labeled \"coffee,\" \"tea,\" \"Coke\" and what?","options": ["Fresca","V8","Yoo-hoo","A&W"],"answer": "Fresca"},
    {"question": "Which First Lady was a ninth-generation descendant of Pocahontas?","options": ["Helen Taft","Edith Wilson","Bess Truman","Mamie Eisenhower"],"answer": "Edith Wilson"},
    {"question": "What great thinker's death is attributed to a chill he caught while stuffing a chicken with snow for an experiment on refrigeration?","options": ["Pythagoras","Archimedes","Isaac Newton","Francis Bacon"],"answer": "Francis Bacon"},
    {"question": "According to the Population Reference Bureau, what is the approximate number of people who have ever lived on earth?","options": ["50 billion","100 billion","1 trillion","5 trillion"],"answer": "100 billion"},
    {"question": "Who delivered the less famous two-hour speech that preceded Abraham Lincoln's two-minute Gettysburg Address?","options": ["Wendell Phillips","Daniel Webster","Robert G. Ingersoll","Edward Everett"],"answer": "Edward Everett"},
    {"question": "Though today it's treated like a treasure, what famous painting was once cut into to enlarge a doorway?","options": ["Detroit Industry","The Last Supper","Guernica","The Birth of Venus"],"answer": "The Last Supper"},
    {"question": "Who once wrote, \"'Bartlett's Familiar Quotations' is an admirable work,\" a quotation now listed in \"Bartlett's Familiar Quotations\"?","options": ["Truman Capote","John Lennon","Winston Churchill","Mark Twain"],"answer": "Winston Churchill"},
    {"question": "The most-watched TV episode of all time, the final episode of \"M*A*S*H\" aired at 8:30 PM, on February 28, 1983 following what sitcom?","options": ["Private Benjamin","Square Pegs","Alice","Newhart"],"answer": "Alice"},
    {"question": "\"Nephelococcygia\" is the practice of doing what?","options": ["Finding shapes in clouds","Sleeping with your eyes open","Breaking glass with your voice","Swimming in freezing water"],"answer": "Finding shapes in clouds"},
    {"question": "In a failed assassination attempt, what U.S. president was shot at twice at point-blank range, but survived because both guns misfired?","options": ["John Adams","Andrew Jackson","James Polk","Martin Van Buren"],"answer": "Andrew Jackson"},
    {"question": "A rare example of a word that rhymes with \"orange,\" the Blorenge is a what?","options": ["River in Ireland","Forest in Scotland","Mountain in Wales","Desert in Australia"],"answer": "Mountain in Wales"},
    {"question": "In addition to his career as an astrologer and \"prophet,\" Nostradamus published a 1555 treatise that included a section on what?","options": ["Training parrots to talk","Cheating at card games","Digging graves","Making jams and jellies"],"answer": "Making jams and jellies"},
    {"question": "Compiled by Benjamin Franklin in 1737, \"The Drinker's Dictionar\" included all but which of these synonyms for \"drunkenness\"?","options": ["Nimptopsical","Buzzey","Pifflicated","Staggerish"],"answer": "Pifflicated"},
    {"question": "On the periodic table, there are four different elements named after what?","options": ["Antoine Lavoisier's pet cat","A moon of Neptune","Marie Curie's maiden name","A Swedish mining village"],"answer": "A Swedish mining village"},
    {"question": "When scientists tested it with an electroencephalogram, which of these food items produced readings similar to a human brain?","options": ["Wint-O-Green Life Saver","SPAM","Lime Jell-O","Jet-Puffed Marshmallow"],"answer": "Lime Jell-O"},
    {"question": "Which of the following is not the title of a country song released by Netflix phenomenon Joe Exotic, aka the \"Tiger King\"?","options": ["I Saw a Tiger","Big-Hearted Cat","Here Kitty Kitty","King of the Beast"],"answer": "Big-Hearted Cat"},
    {"question": "Althrough he and his wife never touched a light switch for fear of being shocked, who was the first president to have electricity in the White House?","options": ["Ulysses S. Grant","Benjamin Harrison","Chester A. Arthur","Andrew Johnson"],"answer": "Benjamin Harrison"},
    {"question": "Not including blanks or bonus spaces, the highest-valued three-letter Scrabble word is \"zax\", which is a what?","options": ["Rare species of African antelope","Ceramic container for holy water","Letter in the Arabic alphabet","Tool for cutting roofing slates"],"answer": "Tool for cutting roofing slates"},
    {"question": "Which compass point lies midway between east and north-east?","options": ["East-north-east","North-east-north","East-east-north"," North-north-east"],"answer": "East-north-east"},
    {"question": "Who wrote the novel 'The Turn of the Screw'?","options": ["EM Foster","Christopher Isherwood","Henry James","John Galsworthy"],"answer": "Henry James"},
    {"question": "The 'K'K point is a measurement used in which sport?","options": ["Triple Jump","Curling","Rifle Shooting","Ski Jumping"],"answer": "Ski Jumping"},
    {"question": "The word 'Kismet' meaning 'fate' comes from which language?","options": ["Hungarian","Latin","Swahili","Arabic"],"answer": "Arabic"},
    {"question": "In the Roman Catholic Church, what is a monstrance?","options": ["Priest's robe","Ritual container","Alter cloth","Prayer"],"answer": "Ritual container"},
    {"question": "Discovery is a variety of which fruit?","options": ["Apple","Banana","Plum","Strawberry"],"answer": "Apple"},
    {"question": "The heaviest bird of prey is what kind of bird?","options": ["Hawk","Owl","Condor","Kestrel"],"answer": "Condor"},
    {"question": "Which of these is most likely to be used to stuff cushions?","options": ["Kaolin","Kabuki","Kapok","Kama"],"answer": "Kapok"},
    {"question": "Which of these composers is buried in Poets' Corner in Westminster Abbey?","options": ["J Brahms","F Liszt","R Wagner","G F Handel"],"answer": "G F Handel"},
    {"question": "Which of these conditions is caused by a deficiency in B1?","options": ["Rickets","Scurvy","Beriberi","Malaria"],"answer": "Beriberi"},
    {"question": "Sir John Oldcastle is believed to be the prototype for which of Shakespeare’s characters?","options": ["Falstaff","Macbeth","Prospero","Cymbeline"],"answer": "Falstaff"},
    {"question": "In Greek mythology, Atlas was a member of which race?","options": ["Titans","Cyclops","Centaurs","Gorgons"],"answer": "Titans"},
    {"question": "Which mythological creature appears on the flag of Bhutan?","options": ["Dragon","Centaur","Minotaur","Hydra"],"answer": "Dragon"},
    {"question": "In which city did the poet John Keats die?","options": ["Copenhagen","Brussels","Rome","Vienna"],"answer": "Rome"},
    {"question": "In mythology, Orpheous played which instrument?","options": ["Lyre","Flute","Organ","Pan pipes"],"answer": "Lyre"},
    {"question": "Reiki is a healing technique from which country?","options": ["China","Japan","India","Thailand"],"answer": "Japan"},
    {"question": "Orvieto wine comes from which country?","options": ["France","Spain","Germany","Italy"],"answer": "Italy"},
    {"question": "Althorpe is the seat of which British family?","options": ["Beaufort","Cavendish","Percy","Spencer"],"answer": "Spencer"},
    {"question": "In Germany, what kind of building is the Rathaus?","options": ["Cathedral","Hospital","Town Hall","Police Station"],"answer": "Town Hall"},
    {"question": "Which singer launched her own label, Matriarch Records, in 2004?","options": ["Mary J Blige","Madonna","Mariah Carey","Mandy Moore"],"answer": "Mary J Blige"},
    {"question": "What is studied and collected by a vexillologist?","options": ["Feathers","Flags","Wine Corks","Dictionaries"],"answer": "Flags"},
    {"question": "Haakon is a traditional name for kings of which country?","options": ["Belgium","Norway","Greece","Spain"],"answer": "Norway"},
    {"question": "Which country was known for a time as Kampuchea?","options": ["Cambodia","Cameroon","Chad","China"],"answer": "Cambodia"},
    {"question": "Who wrote the children's story 'How the Leopard Got His Spots'?","options": ["JK Rowling","Rudyard Kipling","Edward Lear","Lewis Carroll"],"answer": "Rudyard Kipling"},
    {"question": "The city of Timbuktu stands close to the bank of which river?","options": ["Nile","Congo","Niger","Zambezi"],"answer": "Niger"},
    {"question": "On which continent is the Istria peninsular?","options": ["Asia","Africa","Europe","South America"],"answer": "Europe"}
]